Ruth Frances Woodsmall Papers, 1863-1968
Sophia Smith Collection
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1915-1967; 4.25 linear ft
  There are three sections in the Subject subseries: Conferences, Countries, World War I, and World War II. The bulk of the photographs are contained in the Countries, World War I and World War II sections. Woodsmall traveled widely, especially for the YWCA and for the Laymen's Foreign Mission Inquiry. The countries section contains a substantial collection of photographs from twenty countries, especially China and Turkey. Although many have minimal identification and/or are undated, they provide a rich and valuable insight into the status of women especially in the Middle and Far East. Photographs for Women and the New East are located in this section. The World War I section contains British photographs of farm workers and war industries as well as war work in France. The World War II section contains photographs of WAACs and WRENs, scenes, and war work.
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1927-1956; 1 linear ft
  This series consists primarily of Chinese memorabilia. In addition there are photographs of Hubert Woodsmall, HICOG and UN activities; 24 glass slide negatives of women and World War I; Woodsmall's honorary degree certificate and academic hood; Laymen's Foreign Missions Inquiry reports, and her passport.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  - Eldredge, Helen Woodsmall
    - Articles, printed materials, and miscellaneous biographical material, 1910-56, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Indian Vignettes," undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Neumann
    - Marlen (Eldredge), 1936, 1953-54, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Robert: broadcasts, speeches, and writings, 1949, 1952-54, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Woodsmall
    - Harrison, 1876, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hubert, 1945, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mary Howes, [see also SERIES II. BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL MATERIALS-Mary Howes Woodsmall Memorial Foundation] (Box 1)
      - Obituary, diary excerpts, and memorabilia, 1863-78, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Estate, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ruth (Box 1)
      - Articles and clippings, 1919-63, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Bible with inserts, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Biographical sketches and vitae, 1933-62, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Birth certification, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Degrees, certificates, and school material, 1902-61 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Honors (Box 2)
        - Commander's Cross of the Order of Merit (Germany) (Box 2)
          - Correspondence, certificate, and printed material, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
          - Award, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        - Honorary degrees (Box 2)
          - Indiana University (1956), 1955-56, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 2, Folder 4)
          - University of Nebraska (1945), 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - International Federation of Business and Professional Women, Ford Foundation Grant, 1953-54 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Kappa Alpha Theta, 1952, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Lecture engagements, 1933-34, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Memorabilia, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 2)
        - Letters of introduction and recommendations, 1903-44, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Identification cards and finger prints, 1920-52, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - Invitations, 1907-59, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - Passports and visas, 1883-1961, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - School books (foreign), 1929, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Visiting cards, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous, 1891-63, n.d (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
      - Will, 1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- SERIES II. BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL MATERIALS
  - Miscellaneous, 1911-52 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Insurance, 1915-61 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mary Howes Woodsmall Memorial Foundation, 1949-57 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - YWCA retirement, 1925-45, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Investments, 1935-60 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - Account books, 1911-26 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Family
    - Woodsmall, Ruth (Box 6)
      - Outgoing (Box 6)
        - Eldredge, Helen Woodsmall (Box 6)
          - 1906 - Jun 1920 (Box 7, Folder 1-10)
          - Jul 1920-1923 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
          - 1924-59 (Box 9, Folder 1-19)
          - undated (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
        - Eldredge, Mark, 1961-62 (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Neumann (Box 10)
          - Marlen Eldredge, 1950-63, undated (Box 10, Folder 5-10)
          - Robert, 1960, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Woodsmall (Box 11)
          - Hubert, 1906-41 (Box 11, Folder 2)
          - Lelia, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
          - Mary E. Howes, 1906-12, undated (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
      - Incoming (Box 11)
        - Eldredge (Box 11)
          - Helen, 1919-62, undated (Box 11, Folder 6-12)
          - Mark, 1932-63 (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - Neumannn (Box 12)
          - Marlen Eldredge, 1924-63, undated (Box 12, Folder 2-9)
          - Robert, 1944-63 (Box 12, Folder 10)
          - Ronald, 1950-62 (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - Willinberg, Susan Woodsmall, 1960-63 (Box 12, Folder 12)
        - Woodsmall (Box 12)
          - Hubert, 1923-62 (Box 12, Folder 13-15)
          - Hubert Jr. and Claribel, 1961-62 (Box 12, Folder 16)
          - Lelia, 1920, 1940-63 (Box 12, Folder 17)
          - Mary Howes, 1900-12, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Eldredge, Helen (Box 12)
      - Woodsmall, Mary Howes, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Guthrie, Annie, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Neumann, Marlen Eldredge (Box 13)
      - Christmas letters, 1967-68 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Family, 1938-39, 1955-60, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1957-61 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Woodsmall, Harrison, 1874, 1887 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Woodsmall, Mary Howes, 1851-1912, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1886-1913, n.d (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Friends and associates
    - A, 1933-61, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Lucy W., 1955-56 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Agnew, Helen, 1944-49 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Allport, Mildred, 1952-61 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Antin, Mary, 1916-17 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - B, 1931-62, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Baehnish, Theanolte, 1953-57 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Baldwin, Mary W., 1943-44 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Barnes, Lilace, 1941-60, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Bartlett, Lucy, 1952-62, n.d (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Bayouth, Edna, 1957-61 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Benade, Miriam McGraw, 1931-49 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Berkman, Emily, 1952-54 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Bertrand, Alice, 1935-41 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Birjand, Parren, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Blatchford, Virginia, 1961-63 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Bowles, Luanna, 1947-63 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Bracey, Bertha, 1951-52 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Bretherton, Gladys, 1960-61 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Bristol, Mark L., 1931-38 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Brown, Mary Beth, 1958-59 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Buck, Pearl, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - C, 1928-61, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Cabisius, Marie Therese, 1951-63 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Caspar, Adelheid, 1951-52 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Chamberlain, Elizabeth, 1934-56 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Churchill, Clementine, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Clarke, Elizabeth, 1952-61 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Crowdy, Eleanor Rachael, 1928, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - D, 1928-62, undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Devasahayam, Lily, 1931-32 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Dinkins, William, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Dittmer, Inge, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Dodd, Isabel, 1932-43, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Dodge, Baynard, 1928, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - E -F, 1935-62, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Epling, Ruth and Clary, 1947-54) (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Faymy, Sumaya, 1955-61 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Finley, Martha, 1927-46 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - To "Friends", 1941-62 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Fox, Evelyn, 1940-61, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - G, 1935-62, undated (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Galbraith, Winifred, 1947-59, undated (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Gandhi, Mohandas K., 1928-29 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Gilfallan, Irma, 1937-59 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Glaser, Annelise, 1952-62 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Graff, Esther, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Griess, Matilda 1958-61 (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Grierson, Margaret Storrs, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Guthrie, Anne, 1940-61, undated (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - H, 1932-62, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Hess, Bertha, 1941-52 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Hickey, Margaret, 1948-52 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Hiller, Margaret, 1958-61, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Hinkley, Lelia, 1959-62 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Hocking, William Ernest, 1932-61 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Hudson, Bradford, 1958-59 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Hudson, Manley, 1927-28 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Hyndman, Margaret, 1957-58 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - I-J, 1935-63, n.d (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Jones, Jesse, 1928, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - K, 1935-61, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Kato, Taka, 1938-39, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Kaufman, Emma, 1958-59 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Kuan, M. J., 1933 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - L, 1938-61, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Lamont, Elizabeth, 1934-46, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Lanzrath, Sigrid, 1952-62, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Lemke, Antse, 1949-61 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Littell, Franklin, 1956-58 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Lohmann, Hanni, 1952-57 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Lowrie, Helen, 1942-56 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Luxmore, Ethel, 1940-60, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - M, 1929-62, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Maffett, Dr. Minnie L., 1952, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - McClelland, Dalton, 1961, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - McCloy, John and Eleanor, 1953, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - McCulloch, Rhoda, 1937-43 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Mayston, Elizabeth, 1930-62 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Menon, Lakshmi, 1959-61 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Miller, Frieda, 1952-61 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Moreland, Helen Hall, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - N, 1934-61 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Nehru, Jawaharal, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Nicoll, Dorothea, 1962-63, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Nichol, Helen, 1946, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - O-P, 1928-62, undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Patrick, Mary Mills, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Pendleton, Marion, 1959-62 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Perkins, Frances, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Pithavadian, Lily, 1932-34 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Probst, Maria, 1952-53 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Q-R, 1928-60, undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Rajwade, Lakshmibai, 1932-47 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Rama Rau, B. L., 1931 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Rangarao, Santhi, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Rice, Anna V., 1935-40 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Ricker, Christine, 1960-62 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Jr. and Abby, 1933-34, 1941, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1934, 1948-54 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Royce, Marion, 1949-61, undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - S, 1910-63, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Shabandar, Kay, 1953-59 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Anne, 1961-63 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Snyder, Harry and Olive, 1956-59, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Strong, Tracy, 1947-62, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - T, 1933-62, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Takeda, Kiyo, 1941, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Truman, Harry, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - U-V, 1932-62, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Van de Wall, Cara Marie, 1952-58 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Van Ess, Dorothy, 1960-62 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Von Velsen, Dorothee, 1952-55 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - W, 1933-63, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Wampler, Fred, 1928-31 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Washburne, Elizabeth, 1959-60 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Weld, Ernest, 1933-34 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Woodhouse, Going Chase, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Wrinkle, William L. 1957-62 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Y-Z, 1936-63, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Zarnack, Hulda, 1945-62 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified (Box 16)
      - By first name, 1935-63 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous, 1933-59 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Third party: Mary R. Beard to Mrs. Blaisdell, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES
  - Diaries
    - 1905-17 (Box 17)
    - 1918-31 (Box 18)
    - 1934-62 (Box 19)
  - Notes
    - Countries (Box 19)
      - China, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Egypt, 1910-32 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Greece, 1925, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - India, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - New Zealand, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Russia, 1920-23 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
      - Notebooks (8), 1921-46, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Economics Course, Geneva, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Student themes, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - General and unidentified, 1943, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Speeches and broadcasts, 1930-56, undated (Box 22, Folder 1-8)
  - Publications and reports
    - "Changing Status of Moslem Women" (Rockefeller Grant) (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, 1927-35 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
      - Itineraries, 1928-29 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Statistics, articles, reports, notes and printed material (Box 23)
        - Egypt, 1927-29 (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - India, 1926-29, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
        - Lebanon, 1929, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
        - Palestine, 1928-29, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
        - Persia, 1925-29, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
        - Syria, 1927-30, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
        - Turkey, 1923-30, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous, 1927, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Speeches, 1927-29, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Articles translated by native students and secretaries, Egypt, 1922-28, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Student essays on Moslem women, 1929, undated (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      - "Translation Service, Current Turkish Press", 1930-31 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Bound reports (5 v.), 1928-30 (Box 25)
      - Manuscript notes, 1928-30 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Eastern Women Today and Tomorrow, [see SERIES V. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES - Laymen's Foreign Mission Inquiry] (Box 25)
    - Moslem Women Enter the New World (Box 25)
      - Correspondence (Box 25)
        - Contractual, 1935-36 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Post publication, 1936-56, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1933-35, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Drafts, undated (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
      - Reports and contracts, 1933, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1932-34, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Translation service articles, 1932-34, n.d (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Published edition (2 copies), 1933 (Box 27)
    - Study of the Role of Women in Lebanon, Egypt, Iraq, Jordan and Syria (Box 27)
      - Typescript and 2 published copies, 1956 (Box 28)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 28)
        - Contacts, recommendations, etc., 1954-55 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Business and financial material, 1954-55 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1954-56, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Press releases and progress reports, 1954-55 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Reports from countries on various organizations, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Egypt (Box 28)
        - Interviews, 1954-55, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Conferences (Box 29)
          - Conference on Compulsory and Free Education for Arab States in Cooperation with UNESCO and Arab League, 1950-54 (Box 29, Folder 2)
          - Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - Discussion group meetings, 1954-55 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Reports, 1954-55 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Speeches: Ahmed Hussein, 1953-55 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous projects, writings, and printed material, 1947-55, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Iraq (Box 29)
        - Interviews, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - Printed material, 1953-55 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        - Reports and miscellaneous material, 1954-55 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Jordan (Box 29)
        - Interviews, 1955, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - Printed material, 1952-55, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
        - Reports, 1953-56, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Lebanon (Box 29)
        - Interviews, 1954-55 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Reports, 1943-55, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Syria (Box 30)
        - Interviews, 1954-55, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - Reports, 1952-55, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Women and the New East (Box 30)
      - Correspondence (Box 30)
        - Contacts, 1956-57 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Pre-publication, 1956-60, undated (Box 31, Folder 2-5)
        - Post-publication, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Proposals, introductions, contracts, etc., 1956-60 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Reviews, 1960-61 (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
      - Typescript (2 vols.) (Box 32)
      - Published book, 1960 (Box 33)
      - Reports, interviews, and correspondence (Box 33)
        - Afghanistan, 1955-59 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - India (Box 33)
          - Correspondence, 1956-58 (Box 33, Folder 2)
          - Interviews, 1956-57 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
          - Reports, 1956-59 (Box 33, Folder 5)
        - Indonesia (Box 33)
          - Interviews, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 1)
          - Reports, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - Iran (Box 34)
          - Correspondence, 1956-58 (Box 34, Folder 3)
          - Interviews, 1956-58 (Box 34, Folder 4)
          - Reports, 1954-59 (Box 34, Folder 5)
        - Iraq, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Lebanon, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Pakistan (Box 34)
          - Correspondence, 1956-60 (Box 34, Folder 8)
          - Interviews, 1947-57 (Box 34, Folder 9)
          - Reports and miscellaneous materials, 1956-61 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        - Turkey (Box 34)
          - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 34, Folder 11)
          - Interviews, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 12)
          - Reports and miscellaneous materials, 1955-57 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
      - Encyclopedia Britannica article "Harem," 1962 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Interview with Eleanor Roosevelt, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - "That they may not have died in vain," 1920 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - "With the peoples of France," undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - "Women in the New Germany," 1934-35 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1935-46, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
- SERIES V. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES
  - "Baptist Home Mission Study,"
    - Correspondence, 1934-35 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Schedules and forms, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - "Study of the Baptist Home Mission Program:" personal interviews (Vol. III), 1934-35 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Commission on Christian Education In Japan
    - Correspondence, 1931-32 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Meetings and reports, 1930-31 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Programs, 1930-31, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Proposals, 1929, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Questionnaires, undated (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
    - Interviews, 1930-31 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - "Christian Education In Japan: A Study, International Missionary Council," 1932 (Box 37)
  - Committee of Correspondence
    - Correspondence (Box 37)
      - Anderson, Connie, 1940-62, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Mahon, Charlotte, 1932-46, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Workshops (Box 38)
      - Asian, 1957, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Moslem East, 1918-49, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - "Workshop 1960", 1960 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1936-48, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Laymen's Foreign Mission Inquiry
    - Administrative and preliminary material (Box 38)
      - Aims, outlines, and introductory material, 1931-32, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - "General index of all material supplementing printed reports," undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Invoices and receipts, 1931-32 (Box 39, Folder 1-7)
    - Commissions (Box 39)
      - Appraisal, 1932 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Fact finding (Box 40)
        - Correspondence, 1932-33 (Box 40, Folder 2)
        - Meetings, 1932 (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
        - "Report of the Fact-Finding Commission - India-Burma," undated (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, 1930-34 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
    - Interviews and conferences (Box 41)
      - Burma, 1930-31 (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
      - China, 1932 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
      - India, 1930-31 (Box 42, Folder 1-4)
      - Japan, 1931-32 (Box 43, Folder 1-6)
      - Questionnaires (Box 43)
        - Key to replies (Box 44, Folder 1)
        - Ia-IIc, 1931, undated (Box 44, Folder 2-9)
        - IId-IIj, undated (Box 45, Folder 1-6)
      - Women's interests and activities, undated (Box 45, Folder 7-8)
      - Women's Christian College, Madras, 1931, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Reports (Box 45)
      - Interim (Box 45)
        - Administrative, 1932, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Agricultural, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Bible women's work, 1929-31, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Christian missions effect on India, 1931, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
        - Cinema, 1931, n .d. (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Denominational, 1931-32, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - Economics and industry, 1932, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - Education, 1922-32, undated (Box 46, Folder 8-10)
        - Literature and publications, 1932, undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Medical, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
        - Music and liturgy, 1932, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
        - Rural Christianity in India, 1931, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
        - Women's interests, 1931, undated (Box 47, Folder 5-6)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 47)
          - Daily activity reports, 1931 (Box 47, Folder 7)
          - Visits to missions, 1932, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Final (Box 47)
        - 1932 (Box 48, Folder 1)
        - Book II-IV, 1921-31, undated (Box 48, Folder 2-5)
        - Appendix and notes, 1930-31, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Charts (India), 1927-30, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
      - Presentation plans, 1933-34 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Publicity and printed material, 1932, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Speech by Ruth Woodsmall, 1933 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - "Foreign Missionaries" by M.K. Ghandi, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Eastern Women Today and Tomorrow (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1930-34, undated (Box 49)
      - Dramatization, undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Reviews and publicity and miscellaneous material, 1933-34, undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Speech by Ruth Woodsmall, undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Published book (2 copies), 1933 (Box 49)
    - Re-Thinking Missions: A Laymen's Inquiry After One Hundred Years by the Commission of Appraisal, William Ernest Hocking, Chairman, (New York, Harper Bros, 1932) (Box 49)
  - Liaison Committee of Women's International Organizations, 1938-62, undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Michi Kawai Christian Fellowship, 1939-46 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - United Nations
    - Commission on the Status of Women (Box 50)
      - Women in Agriculture, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954-63, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "Newsletter on the Status of Women," 1954-63 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Political Rights of Women, 1962-63 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Seminar on Civic Responsibilities and Increased Participation of Asian Women in Public Life (Box 50)
      - Reports (Draft), parts 1 and 2, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Working Papers, A-D, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1957, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)